他根本没病
He is not sick.
莱利医生呕吐不止  很明显没法讲课
Dr. Riley is throwing up. He obviously can't lecture.
你亲眼看见他吐了  还是他说的
You witnessed the spew? Or you just have his word for it?
我感觉自己得了淋病
I think I'm coming down with a little bit of the clap.
可能得回家休息几天
I may have to go home for a few days.
莱利医生从没对我撒过谎
Dr. Riley doesn't have a history of lying to me.
你说过这是他今年第五次不上课了
You said this is the fifth time he's missed a class this year.
要么他是病入膏肓  要么就是撒谎
Either he's dying or he's lying.
我免你两个小时的门诊
I'll give you two hours off clinic duty.
好  我让卡梅隆去
Fine. I'll have Cameron do it.
她最喜欢传道授业解惑
She loves inspiring the inspired.
-得你去  -为啥老是我
- You'll do it. - Why is it always me?
因为你人缘差
Because the world hates you.
或者因为这是节诊断课
Or because it's a class on diagnostics.
看哪个答案更满足你的自恋心理
Pick whichever reason feeds your narcissism better.
老子不干
I'm not doing it.
你该拦住我  重新谈判的
You're supposed to stop me. Renegotiate.
而你该继续往前走
And you were supposed to keep on walking.
抱歉  咱俩都没按规矩来  再来
Sorry. Guess we both screwed up. Go on. Do it again.
我去上课  免我四小时的门诊
I'll do the lecture for four hours off clinic.
两小时  我知道你宁愿花几小时
Two. I know you'd rather spend a couple of hours
听自己说话  也不愿在这儿问诊
listening to yourself than listening to patients.
20分钟后开课
Class starts in 20 minutes.
豪斯医生  有病人找你
Dr. House, there's a patient.
我得要走了  有事儿找卡迪
I'm outta here. Take it up with Cuddy.
格雷戈
Greg.
史黛西
Hi, Stacy.
你好吗
How ya doin'?
你问我好吗
How am I doing?
过去这五年就好像...
The last five years have been like--
你有没看过《美女也疯狂》[成人影片]
You ever see those Girls Gone Wild videos?
你就那样活着  还是你就靠看那片活着
Your life's been like that? Or your life's been spent watching them?
我很想你
I have missed you.
所以你才来的吗
Is that why you're here?
我是来找你帮忙的
I need your help.
-这是谁的病历  -我丈夫的
- Who am I looking at? - My husband.
病人感觉腹痛  并伴有间歇性晕眩
Who is suffering abdominal pain and fainting spells.
没有肿瘤  也不是血管炎
No sign of tumors, no vasculitis.
可能是消化不良
Could be indigestion.
或是肾结石  小小一颗就会很痛苦
Or maybe a kidney stone. Little one can pack a lot of wallop.
你以为我不会结婚  是吗
Did you think I wasn't going to get married?
至少不是跟身体这么差的
Not to someone so poorly endowed.
这家伙胰脏太烂了
This guy's pancreas is pathetic.
不是肾结石  也不是消化不良
There is no kidney stone, no indigestion.
换了三家医院五个医生都查不出病因
Three hospitals, five doctors-- Not one of them found anything.
也许本来就没什么病
Maybe there's nothing to be found.
是啊  就好比你会突然信任医生
Right. You suddenly trust doctors,
喜欢宠物和雨中散步
love puppies and long walks in the rain.
我的腿没法散步
Walks are out.
相处久了  对方有不对劲自然知道
I was around you long enough to know when something's not right.
马克性情大变  行为古怪没有连贯性
Mark's had personality changes. He's acting strange, disconnected.
有意思
Interesting.
就是说不是神经问题
Means there's either a neurological component,
就是有了外遇
or he's having an affair.
没有外遇  什么都没有  他就是病了
No affair. No nothing. He's sick.
我知道你不太忙  你躲工作跟躲瘟疫似的
I know you're not too busy. You avoid work like the plague.
除非真有瘟疫
Unless it actually is the plague.
-我请你帮忙  -我是不太忙
- I'm asking you a favor. - I'm not too busy.
但不确定想不想救他
But I'm not sure I want him to live.
很高兴再见到你
It's good seeing you again.
有三个人来看门诊
Three guys walk into a clinic.
都说腿疼  会是什么病
Their legs hurt. What's wrong with them?
你知道我不待见你的  是吧
I'm not gonna like you, am I?
腿疼最可能的原因就是肌肉劳损
The most likely cause of leg pain is muscle strain.
热敷并放松疼痛部位
Apply heat and rest affected areas.
统计学上说  你说得对  很好
Statistically, you're right. Very good.
以我的经验
My experience,
半数以上腿疼都是骨骼肌系统问题
over half of leg pain is musculoskeletal,
一般是由于过度锻炼引起的
generally from excessive exercise,
12%是因怀孕导致静脉曲张而引起的
Twelve percent is varicose veins brought on by pregnancy,
其余大部分都是交通事故
and most of the rest is the result of vehicular accidents.
三个人  就有六条退
I said three people. That's six legs.
所以其中三条是运动过度  两条是交通意外
So you've got three hurt jogging, two in collisions,
还有一条是因为怀孕
and one of the legs is pregnant.
疼痛发生时  他们都在干什么
What were they doing when pain presented?
-我不知道  -你没问病史吗
- I have no idea. - You didn't ask? You didn't take a history?
当然  但所知的仅限于病人自述
Of course. But all that told us is what they said happened.
病人甲  农夫  说他当时正在修栅栏
Person "A", farmer, says he was fixing a fence.
突然脚踝疼痛  肌肉失去控制
Tightness in the ankle, loss of muscle control.
病人乙   排球运动员
Person "B", volleyball practice.
教练认为是肌肉拉伤
Coach figured it was a pulled muscle.
病人丙  卡门·伊莱克特拉正在打高尔夫
And "C", we've got Carmen Electra golfing.
-好球  -你治过《海滩护卫队》里的妞吗
- Yes! - Whoa. You treated the Baywatch chick?
应该说是《海滩护卫队》的演员  没
The Baywatch thespian. And no.
我得假设每个病人的身份
I gotta disguise the identity of each of the patients,
我厌倦了总拿中年男子举例
and I got tired of using the middle-aged man.
卡门看来是个不错的选择
Carmen seemed like a pleasant alternative.
而且  她高尔夫也打得不错
Also, she's apparently quite the golfer.
在接下来两小时内  三人中的一个...
In less than two hours, one of these three...
将被扔出医院
will be tossed out of the hospital
因为他是装病来骗麻醉剂的
because they were faking it to score narcotics,
一人将生命垂危
and one will be very close to death.
猜得出是谁吗
Any guesses on which is which?
好吧  先从农夫讲起
Okay, I say we start with the farmer.
你徒步走到栅栏的吗  有多远
Did you hike to the fence, and how far?
是的  离我的农庄差不多半英里
Yes. It's about a half a mile from my farmhouse.
哪儿疼
Where is the pain localized?
从脚踝开始  往上都疼
It started just above my ankle, and it's radiating up.
那么  我们该先做什么
So, what should we do first?
问家族病史
Family history?
腿疼的病史  这可不多
Indicative of leg pain? That's a very short list.
家族中有无骨癌
Any history of bone cancer,
成骨不全或多发性骨髓瘤病史
osteogenesis imperfecta or multiple myeloma?
可能是血液问题
Could be a blood issue.
应做全血球计数和血浆D二聚体检测
We should run a C.B.C. and a D-Dimer.
再做个核磁共振
And get an M.R.I.
核磁共振还是PET扫描
M.R.I. or a PET scan?
要是血管的问题  最好...
If the problem's vascular, he's better off--
抱歉  谢谢参与
Sorry. Thanks for playin'.
病人已死  你们害死的
Patient's dead. You killed him.
根本没时间做检测  我们也无能为力
We had no time to run any tests. There was nothing we could do.
至少有时间看看病人的腿
You had time to look at the leg.
不是说先从农夫讲起吗
I thought we were starting with the farmer's case first.
没错  不过要看腿的话...
We are. But if we're gonna look at a leg--
你得脱了裤子
I need you to take off your pants.
有创伤
Puncture.
-蛇咬的  -我也会这么猜
- Snakebite. - That would be my guess.
农夫不知道自己被蛇咬吗
Farmer didn't know he'd been bitten by a snake?
他是这么说的
That's what he said.
突感刺痛  高茎草地  什么都没看见
Sudden shooting pain, tall grass. Never saw a thing.
-是哪种蛇  -你想让我
- What kind of snake? - You want me to tell you
单凭腿上的创口就说出是哪种蛇吗
what kind of snake it was from the shape of the hole in the leg?
不知道是哪种蛇的话
How are we to know what kind of antivenom to use
怎么能确定用哪种抗蛇毒血清
if we don't know what kind of snake it is?
会有人去找答案的
Oh, there are people to find those things out.
难道不该等动物保护协会之类的吗
Shouldn't we wait for the Humane Society or something?
那人可能仅剩几小时可活了
Guy might only have a couple of hours.
等动物保护协会派人来的同时
And while we wait for the Humane Society to show up,
不如先去看看排球运动员的情况
what say we check in on the volleyball player.
你有肌腱炎
You have tendinitis.
这人多大年纪
How old is this person?
我是说
I mean,
不会真有40岁中年男人混在女排队里的吧
it's not really a 40-year-old man on a girls' volleyball team, right?
看的是腿  腿就是腿
It's a leg. A leg is a leg is a leg.
我只是担心...
Well, I was just worried that--
她要是再年轻点  你是否会加倍担心
Would you worry about her more if she was younger?
当然我们该关心所有病人
Obviously, we should care about all our patients,
不管多大年纪...
no matter what age--
对  我看到你盯着卡门那小样了
Yeah, right. I saw the way you were looking at Carmen.
她是我的  离她远点
She's mine. Stay away.
-你会给你妈妈动手术吗  -当然不
- Would you operate on your mother? - Of course not.
我肯定会太紧张  不能客观处理
I'd be too nervous. Couldn't be objective.
那为什么都急于视患者如家人般对待
Then why are you so anxious to treat every patient like they're family?
实际的病人16岁
The actual patient is 16.
医生关心过多  就会这样
Here's what happens when doctors care too much.
告诉我你所有的情况
I need to know everything about you.
我追溯了其家族三代
I went back three generations.
无癌症  帕金森或其他病变史
No history of cancer, Parkinson's or any other degenerative condition.
但她们学校有个男孩
But there's this boy at school,
是校排球队的
and he's on the boys' volleyball team.
在派对上俩人好上了  从此再没联系过她
They made out at a party, and now he won't call her back.
她一个同学说
And this friend of hers at school said
那男孩从没喜欢过她
this boy didn't like her and never did.
让你去检查她的膝盖  你就问回来这些
You got all this from an examination of the knee?
我觉得她很抑郁
I think she's depressed.
她没有肌腱炎吗
She doesn't have tendinitis?
-有肌腱炎  -那她是因此而抑郁吗
- She has tendinitis. - She's depressed about having tendinitis?
她抑郁的原因跟患肌腱炎的原因一样
She's depressed for the same reason that she has tendinitis.
-不是那男孩?  -不  那男孩是个混蛋
- Not the boy?  - No, the boy's a jerk.
她自己清楚但仍很抑郁
She knows that, and yet she's depressed.
我发现个小瘤
I found a nodule.
是甲状腺问题  引发情绪抑郁
Ahh. Problems with the thyroid gland-- causes depressed mental state...
也可以导致肌腱发炎
can cause inflammation of the tendons.
我会去做测试
I'll run the tests.
这么说  正是因为她的极度关注
So because she took such an extreme interest,
才能发现那人甲状腺有问题
she found out that the person had a thyroid condition.
不对  因为关注  她发现个极小的瘤
No. Because she took such an interest, she discovered a tiny nodule...
本来无关紧要  却让我们别无选择
which in reality signified nothing but gave us no choice...
让肌腱炎病人去做又贵又痛的检测
but to put a person with tendinitis through an expensive and painful test.
真正处理得当的医生  会这样看病
Here's how a well-adjusted doctor handles a case.
现在我能穿上裤子了吧
Can I put my pants back on now?
最好不要
I'd rather you didn't.
这是哪位卡门·伊莱克特拉
Which Carmen Electra is this?
开始那位  打高尔夫的
The first one. The golfer.
那她为什么没穿裤子
Then why isn't she wearing pants?
你膝盖肌腱的反射能力下降
You have decreased reflexes in your patellar tendon.
-谁能来说下  -椎间盘突出
- Anyone? - Slipped disc.
有可能  有多痛
Could be. How bad does it hurt?
-真的很痛很痛  -真的
- It hurts really, really bad. - Yeah?
看起来不像真的  她是装病的那位吗
It doesn't seem real. Is she the one faking?
看在上帝份上
Oh, for God's sake.
请她来是为了满足我的幻想
She's here to play into my fantasy,
又不是因为演技
not 'cause she's Meryl Streep.
好吧
Fine.
我到底得了什么病
What the hell is wrong with me!
快帮帮我
Do something!
这么疼不像是椎间盘突出
Too much pain to be a slipped disc.
内容物疝出  压迫到了神经根
Could be herniated and impinging the nerve root.
或者是腹股沟区牵涉痛
Or it could be referred pain from his groin.
先生  还有其他部位疼痛吗
Sir, are you getting pain anywhere else?
他蜷着身子  肯定不是后背疼
He's curling. It's not the back.
-先生  你哪里疼  -救救我
- Sir, where are you getting pain?  - Help me!
不先帮他止疼  什么都问不出来
He's not gonna tell us anything if we don't get him out of pain.
给他注射50毫克杜冷丁
Give him 50 milligrams of Demerol.
没有他的病历  会过敏的
We have no history. He could be allergic.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
他不停叫疼  无法诊断
We can't diagnose him while he screams.
总比止痛药过敏致死的好  那就...
Better than killing him with painkillers. That--
显然他没过敏
Apparently he's not allergic.
谢谢  我感觉好多了
Thank you. I feel a lot better now.
我们搞砸了
We screwed up.
不  你们做了主治医师该做的
No. You did exactly what his attending did.
-那就是得当的诊断方式吗  -对
- And that was the proper way to handle the case? - Yeah.
那人显然把这当毒品用
The guy used him as a dealer.
你们以后会见识更多装病骗麻醉剂的
You're gonna see a lot of drug-seeking behavior in your practice.
原因只有一个  这么做见效
There's a reason-- It works.
现在  回到农场
Meanwhile, back on the farm--
没错  是粗鳞响尾蛇
Yeah. Timber rattlesnake.
准备四瓶CroFab抗蛇毒血清
Four vials of the CroFab antivenom.
-你好  感觉如何  -还不错
- Hey, how ya doin'? - All right.
谢谢  注射以后很快就会好的
Thank you. This will start making you feel better really fast.
他有过敏反应  呼吸器
He's having an allergic reaction. Bag.
心脏起搏器
Paddles and epi.
-他的心脏没问题  -很快就会有
- His heart's fine. - It's not gonna stay that way.
心脏起搏器
Paddles!
不如休息五分钟
What say we take five,
喝点咖啡  方便方便
get some coffee, go pee.
你以为她不会结婚吗
You didn't think she was gonna get married?
她也这么问我
She asked me the same question.
怎么  不准备给他治吗
And... what? You're not gonna treat him?
很可能他什么病都没有
There's probably nothing wrong with him.
当然  那也说得通
Oh, sure, that makes sense.
她只是利用丈夫生病这样的老桥段
She's just using the old sick husband routine...
当做重新接近你的借口
as an excuse to get back in touch with you.
你觉得这对她来说容易吗
You think this is easy for her?
她再次靠近你的唯一原因
The only reason she'd be anywhere near you is
只能是别无选择了
if she was desperate.
难道因为她恨我  我就该帮她吗
So I should help her because she hates me?
她并不恨你  她深爱你
She doesn't hate you. She loves you.
她只是无法留在你的身边
She just... can't stand to be around you.
豪斯医生
Uh, Dr. House?
已经休息了将近六分钟了
It's been almost six minutes.
找到了
Found him.
那排球运动员
The volleyball player...
诊断为肌腱炎  注射抗炎药后见效
was responding to the anti-inflammatories as you'd expect in a case of tendinitis.
等下  被蛇咬的那位呢
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. What about the snakebite guy?
我对排球运动员那例不是很感兴趣
I don't really care about the volleyball player.
要是我说排球运动员突然重度中风呢
What if I told you the volleyball player had a sudden massive stroke?
-真的吗  -没有
- Really? - No.
但这样你就会感兴趣了  是吗
But that would make you interested, right?
要是她的甲状腺水平再次降低呢
What if her T-4 came back low?
这本不是好事  但真的话反而能引起医生兴趣
It's not quite as interesting, but it has the benefit of being true.
你说过甲状腺活检只是徒劳
You said the thyroid biopsy was a wasted test.
不  我没这么说  我只是她说让一名
No, I didn't. I said she put a person
患肌腱炎的病人去做又贵又痛苦的检查
with tendinitis through an expensive and painful test.
很显然  病人既有肌腱炎又有甲状腺问题
Apparently, the patient had tendinitis and a thyroid condition.
给你用甲状腺素
We're gonna start you on thyroxine.
能让你病情好转  平复情绪
It'll make you feel better and level your moods.
谢谢
Thank you.
-就这样吗  -你之前是对的
- So that's it? - You were right the first time.
被蛇咬的病例更有趣  其实是恶心
Snakebite guy's way more interesting. Gross, actually.
用肾上腺素后见效
The patient responded to epinephrine,
不再过敏
and the allergic reaction was arrested.
不幸的是  病情仍持续恶化
Unfortunately, the patient continues to deteriorate.
也许不是我们抓的那种蛇咬的
Maybe the snake wrangler was wrong about the type we caught.
毒液测试报告传真过来了
He faxed us the venom test.
确认是粗鳞响尾蛇
Confirmed. It's a timber rattlesnake.
不对  不是的  注意到毒液量那栏吗
No, it's not. Notice the volume?
我大致浏览了性别和颜色
I skimmed over that and the gender and the coloring.
就直接跳过去看蛇的种类了
Jumped right to the name of the snake.
两百毫克毒液  病人是不足四小时前被咬的
Two hundred milligrams. Our guy got bit less than four hours ago.
蛇不可能在短时间内重新生成这么多毒液
There's no way a snake regenerates that much venom that quickly.
我们还得知道蛇生成毒液的速度吗
We're supposed to know how fast snakes make their venom?
不必  除非你的病人被蛇咬了
No. Unless you've got a patient bit by one.
这类知识就有用了
Then it might be helpful.
那我们现在该怎么办
So what do we do now?
他肯定是被其它蛇给咬了  回去再找吧
He must have been bitten by a different snake. We go back and find it.
或者上网  就能查到
Or you go online, and you find
新泽西只有三种常见毒蛇
there's only three poisonous snakes common in New Jersey:
铜头蛇  粗鳞响尾蛇和珊瑚蛇
the copperhead, timber rattler and the coral.
而我们给病人注释的抗蛇毒血清
Copperhead and timber rattler
对铜头蛇和粗鳞响尾蛇都有效
both respond to the antivenoms we gave the guy.
那应该给他注射另一种抗蛇毒血清吗
So we give him the antivenom for the other one?
你这是在问我
Is that a question?
绝对不能盲目再给他用抗蛇毒血清了
We can't just blindly give him another antivenom,
尤其是在第一种差点害死他后
especially after the first one almost killed him.
你说新泽西就三种常见毒蛇
You said only three types of poisonous snakes commonly found in New Jersey.
-那万一是不常见的呢  -很好
- Well, what if this is an uncommon one? - Very good.
-还是得找到到底是哪种  -没必要了
- We gotta find the right snake. - No need.
很可能等我们回来
Odds are by the time you get back,
验尸报告自然会告诉我们是那种蛇
the autopsy results will tell you what kind of snake it was.
但你说...
But you said--
所以还是得给他再用其他血清
So we do give him the antivenom for the other one?
再说一次  你是在问我吗
Again, was that a question?
是我在问你们啊
I asked what you would do.
你把问题扔回给我  好像有失公允
It seems unfair for you to ask me what you would do.
谁选择给他用另一种抗蛇毒血清
Who gives the guy the other antivenom?
谁选择继续去找蛇
And who goes looking for the snake?
我觉得这两个选择  一个杀人  一个救人
I assume that one choice kills him, the other one saves him.
在腿部中毒变黑的情况下
That's usually the way it works
通常只有这两种方法
at the leg-turning-black stage.
所以我们可能杀了他  也可能救了他
So half of us killed him, and half of us saved his life.
-对  -但不该以此谴责我们...
- Yeah. - We can't be blamed for--
我知道这跟你们所学是相违背的
I'm sure this goes against everything you've been taught,
但对错之分确实存在
but right and wrong do exist.
仅仅因为你自己不知道哪个是对
Just because you don't know what the right answer is--
或者根本没办法知道哪个是对
maybe there's even no way you could know what the right answer is--
这样并不会让你的答案变对
doesn't make your answer right or even okay.
其实事情远没那么复杂
It's much simpler than that.
不过是个低级错误
It's just plain wrong.
我们给他用了抗蛇毒血清
We gave the guy the antivenom.
万一我再过敏呢
What if I'm allergic again?
所以这么多医生站在这
That's why these people are here.
一旦你有过敏反应
If you have a reaction,
我们会及时采取必要措施
we're ready to do whatever's necessary...
确保你气道保持通畅  心脏继续跳动
to ensure your airways stay open and your heart keeps beating.
我妻子正在赶来  就不能等等再治吗
My wife's on her way in. Can't this wait?
抱歉  等不了
I'm sorry. It can't.
-我腿又疼了  -他又回来了吗
- It hurts again. - He came back?
通常来说  吸毒的人都很蠢
On average, drug addicts are stupid.
-要是我就报警  -很好
- I'd call the cops. - Good for you.
大部分医生都不会用职业生涯赌这一把
A lot of doctors wouldn't risk their careers on a hunch.
这不算赌  我明知道他是来骗毒品的
It's not a hunch. I mean, I know he wants drugs.
但吸毒的人也有可能生病
Well, even drug addicts get sick.
事实上  出于某种原因
Actually, for some reason,
他们比不吸毒的更常生病
they tend to get sick more often than non-drug addicts.
幸运的是  你不用赌这一把
Luckily, you don't have to play your hunch.
有种更快的解决之道  事实上有好几种
There's a faster way. Actually, there are several.
我更倾向于给他验尿
My preference is urine testing.
但你已经知道他会有毒品反应了
But you already know he has drugs in his system.
我不是想检测的这个
That's not what I'm testing for.
我们会将这根硬橡胶管通过尿道插入你的膀胱
We're gonna put this hard rubber tube up your urethra and into your bladder.
可能会有点不舒服
It may be a little uncomfortable.
难道不该给我来点什么麻醉剂吗
Shouldn't I be getting some sort of anesthetic?
不麻醉  今天我们很怕有过敏反应
We're concerned about allergic reactions today.
如果这人能忍受塑胶管插在鸡鸡里
If the guy can handle a rod in his penis
半小时之久  那他肯定是真病了
for half an hour, he's really sick.
或者他毒瘾真的有够重
Or he's really jonesing.
还是有很多简单办法能搞到毒品的
There's easier ways to get ahold of drugs.
比如说  去其他医院
Other hospitals, for example.
对排球运动员的治疗并不见效
The volleyball player is not responding to treatment.
至少我们不认为有效
At least we think it's not working...
事实上  她的病情恶化了
on account of the fact that she's getting worse.
-还能听到我说话吗  -听不到
- Can you still hear me? - No.
-能听到一点  -听不清
- A little! - Not really!
听不到  怎么知道我问什么
Well, if you can't hear me, how do you know what I asked?
抱歉  哪儿弄疼你了吗
I'm sorry. What did I do?
不知道  但真的很疼
I don't know. It really hurts.
我保证非常小心
I promise to be very careful.
-苏珊  -那不是她真名
- Susan-- - Not her real name.
苏珊  我根本就没碰你
Susan, I barely touched you.
-实在太疼了  -抱歉
- It hurts so much! - I'm sorry.
我一定得抽血  再坚持下
I have to get this blood. Just hold on.
接触感觉过敏
Hypersensitivity to touch.
体内钙离子含量过高吗
Her calcium up?
检查结果超过16
Lab over 16.
问题是为什么  可能原因
Question is why. Likely suspects.
副甲状腺瘤
Parathyroid adenoma.
-肾脏问题  -维生素D中毒
- Kidney problems. - Vit "D" intoxication.
-甲状腺机能亢进  -是由治疗引起的吗
- Hyperthyroid. - Caused by our treatment?
能否慢点讲
Can you please slow down?
最有可能的是腺瘤
The adenoma is most likely.
检查其甲状旁腺素  体内磷含量...
Check her P.T.H., phosphorus
和钙离子含量
and ionized calcium.
再做司他比锝检测
And do a technetium sestamibi.
好了  排球运动员就讲到这里
Okay, that's enough about the volleyball player.
-那农夫现在怎么样  -什么农夫
- What's up with the farmer? - What farmer?
被蛇咬的那位
Snakebite guy.
对了  你们并不知道他
Oh, right. You guys don't know about him.
他是在排球运动员入院三个月后
He doesn't get bitten until three months after
被蛇咬伤来就诊的
we treat the volleyball player.
幸运的是  已经确认时机并未完全延误
Luckily, it's been well established that time is not a fixed construct.
病情没有改善  给他双倍剂量
His condition is not improving. Double the dosage.
-已经加了  -还有种血清
- Already did. - There's another antivenom.
-可能并不有效  但...  -已经试过了
- It's not as effective, but-- - Already tried it.
第一种用的就是  但他过敏
The first stuff, the stuff he was allergic to.
同时用高剂量的类固醇
Gave it to him with high-dose steroids.
-都没有效果  -这些能说明什么
- Nothing's working. - What does it all mean?
-不是那种蛇吗  -已经试遍了所有的血清
- Wrong snake? - We tried every other antivenom we had.
是病情延误太久吗
We're too late?
对  他就快死了  他妻子赶到了
Yep. He's dying. His wife's here.
她总算找到保姆看孩子了  谁去告诉他们噩耗
Finally found a babysitter. Who wants to let 'em know?
-其实我在开玩笑  -他不会死吗
- Actually, I'm kidding. - He's not dying?
不  他是快死了  但并没有妻儿
Oh, yeah, he's dying. But there's no wife and kid.
这太好了
Which is great.
让宣布病人死亡这事更省心了
Makes the breaking-the-news thing way easier.
对了  还有个消息
Oh, yeah. One more piece of news.
吸毒的那家伙开始尿血了
The drug addict is peeing blood.
他们是怎么教你们向家属宣布噩耗的
How do they teach you how to tell someone that they're dying?
就像教建筑师怎么跟人解释
It's kind of like teaching architects how to explain
他们造的房子为何倒塌一样
why their building fell down.
练习时会分角色扮演吗
Do you role-play and stuff?
对  一人去通知死亡
Yeah. One of us gives the bad news,
另一人则扮演家属
and one of us gets the bad news.
那怎么做才能在这门课上拿个优秀呢
What do you have to do to get an "A" in You're Dying 101?
他们会依照你们的亲切度和支持度打分吗
They grade you on gentleness and supportiveness?
有没有个衡量同情的标准
Is there a scale for measuring compassion?
我有个朋友
This buddy of mine--
每次有人感谢他  我都恨不得给他十块钱
I gotta give him 10 bucks every time someone says thank you.
想象下  他实在太好人了
Imagine that. This guy's so good,
即使宣布死亡  人们还是会不住感谢他
people thank him for telling 'em that they're dying.
还差棕色
Needs brown.
我可没收到那么多感谢
I don't get thanked that often.
你快死了
You're dying.
就剩几个小时了
In a few hours.
除了帮你止痛  我们已无能为力了
There's nothing we can do except deal with the pain.
我得回家
Well, I need to go home.
你不能回家
You're not going home.
但我的狗呢  我的狗以后怎么办
But my dog. What will happen to my dog?
颈部没有病变  没有腺瘤
Her neck looks clean. No adenoma.
等下  那家伙快死了  却只关心他的狗吗
Wait, wait, wait. The guy's dying, and all he cares about is his dog?
在你们角色扮演中  有没人遇到过狗狗这回事
Any of you guys go the dog route in your improv sessions?
人类的真理就是  人人皆会说谎
It's a basic truth of the human condition that everybody lies.
唯一的不同是  说什么谎
The only variable is about what.
告诉某人他快死了  最大的好处就是
The great thing about telling someone they're dying...
让他更易聚焦于自己最在乎的事
is that it tends to focus their priorities.
你就能找出他们最关心的问题
You find out what matters to them.
他们愿意为之付诸一切的事
What they're willing to die for.
他们不惜为之说谎的事
What they're willing to lie for.
你肯定会有邻居照顾...
You must have a neighbor who--
邻居们都不喜欢它
Neighbors don't like him.
那动物保护协会的会接管  让它安家
So the Humane Society will take him in and find him a home.
他们才不会  对了  也许我姨妈...
No, they won't. Yeah, but maybe my aunt--
那不是蛇咬的  是吗
It wasn't a snakebite, was it?
我说过我不记得被咬过
I said I don't remember bein' bit.
你当然记得  只是不是蛇咬的
Sure you do. Just not by a snake.
估计前阵子你家恶犬就咬过邻居
I assume that Cujo bit one of your neighbors a while back.
一旦你说是它咬的你  我肯定会上报
You tell me that he bit you, and I gotta report it.
你家恶犬已经有不良记录了  肯定会被处死
Cujo's got a record. He gets the chair.
好消息是你应该死不了了
The good news is you might just live.
坏消息是你的狗非死不可
The bad news is your dog's gonna die.
他就为了救这玩意不惜玩命
Guy risked his life to save this thing?
我来制住它  你去它嘴巴里采样
I'll hold him. You swab the mouth.
我觉得我制住它比较好  你去采样
I think I've got a better grip here. You go for the mouth.
好吧  猜拳决定
All right. I'm odds.
-真的?  -1  2  3
- You serious? - One, two, three!
见鬼
Damn.
我可不管它会不会抓坏你衣服  别松手
I don't care if he's scratching your nads off, you don't let go.
快动手
Just do it!
不如就让那人死了算了
I say we let the guy die.
-我抓住它头了  快动手  -好了
- I got his head. Just do it. - Got it.
这是什么颜色
What would you call that?
是茶色  对吧
It's tea-colored, right?
我们认为单纯为骗毒品而来的那人
The guy we thought was just after the drugs--
尿样呈茶色的话  鉴别诊断是什么
What's the differential diagnosis for urine that's tea-colored?
肾结石
Kidney stone.
-肾结石会导致什么  -尿血
- Kidney stones would cause what? - Blood in urine.
-你的尿是什么颜色的  -黄色
- What color is your pee? - Yellow.
-你的血呢  -红色
- What color is your blood? - Red.
我刚用了哪几种颜色
What colors did I use?
红  黄还有棕色
Red, yellow and brown.
就是棕色  什么会导致棕色尿
And brown. What causes brown?
体内垃圾
Waste.
也就是说他肾脏不工作了  为什么
Which means the kidneys are shutting down. Why?
外伤
Trauma.
他的病历中并未提及
None that his history would indicate.
可能是因私自注射杜冷丁引起的
Could be damage done by the self-injection of the Demerol.
-治疗方式  -热敷及放松...
- Treatment? - Heat and rest--
-还有其他可能原因吗  -感染
- Other possible causes? - Infection.
开始给他用抗生素  还有呢
Start him on antibiotics. What else?
-快  快点想  -我  我不知道
- Come on! Come on! - I-I don't know.
真没用  不过至少还有自知之明
You're useless. But at least you know it.
血检结果显示肌酸激酶超高
Blood tests show elevated creatine kinase.
-这说明什么  -外伤的诊断是正确的
- What does that tell you? - The trauma diagnosis was right.
放松休息几天就会没事的
He takes it easy for a few days, he'll be fine.
你确定?
You sure?
肌酸激酶超高就排除了感染的可能
The elevated C.K. rules out infection--
知道什么比没用更糟吗
You know what's worse than useless?
没用  迟钝
Useless and oblivious.
他们遗漏了什么可能
What are they missing?
你脸板成那样  让我们很难思考
It's kind of hard to think when you're in our face like--
是吗
Yeah?
你觉得面对垂危病人会更容易吗
You think it's gonna be easier when you got a real patient really dying?
你们到底遗漏了什么
What are you missing?
肌肉坏死
Muscle death.
跟你无关
Not your case.
大家一起讨论肯定不是坏事
Nothing wrong with a consult.
肌肉坏死会释放肌红蛋白  对肾脏有毒
Dying muscle leaks myoglobin. It's toxic to the kidneys.
聪明
Brilliant.
给他腿部做核磁共振  看到底什么情况
M.R.I. his leg. See what's killing it.
为何要给那女孩做核磁共振
Why is the girl getting the M.R.I.?
因为她颈部扫描未发现任何甲状腺瘤
Because the neck scan revealed nothing,
而她的医生  比她自己想象得强迫症更加严重
and her doctor's way more obsessive than she thinks she is.
但你说那人需要做核磁共振
But you said the guy needed the M.R.I.
那是因为卡梅隆告诉你们他是肌肉坏死
Because Dr. Cameron back there said muscle death.
你们可没人这么说  他的医生也没人发现
Not one of you said it. Not one of this guy's doctors said it.
他们就让他卧床休息
They gave him bed rest
跟你们一样给他用抗生素
and antibiotics, just like you guys would have.
-那他病情好转了吗  -没有
- Did he get better? - No.
-多久才...  -三天
- How long-- - Three days.
这就是医学的自然规律  你们可能会搞砸
It is in the nature of medicine that you are gonna screw up.
也可能会害死病人
you're gonna kill someone.
没法面对这一事实的话   趁早转行
If you can't handle that reality, pick another profession.
或者读完医学院就去教书
Or finish medical school and teach.
他们用了整整三天才想到可能是肌肉坏死?
Three days before they thought it might have been muscle death?
不  是病人三天后
No, three days before the patient
自己想到可能是肌肉坏死
suggested it might have been muscle death.
核磁共振结果显示是骨肉瘤
The M.R.I. revealed an osteosarcoma.
你大腿骨上有个癌变的肿块
A cancerous tumor on your femur.
需要手术摘除
It needs to be removed surgically.
再经化疗  她生存几率很高
With chemo, she has an excellent chance of survival.
但我必须提醒你
But I have to warn you--
医生将根据你肿瘤的大小和顽固程度
depending on how large the tumor is and how ingrained it is,
决定是否需要截肢
the surgeon may need to amputate your leg.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事的
It's okay.
狗的口腔很脏
Dogs' mouths are pretty filthy,
它们有天生抗体  可消灭大部分细菌
but they have natural antibodies to fight off most of the stuff.
但我们没有  所以被狗咬很危险
We don't. That's why dog bites can be so nasty.
检测结果显示你家狗唾液中含有链球菌
Lab tests of your dog's saliva revealed a type of strep bacteria.
这种病通常被称为坏死性筋膜炎[噬肉病]
It's commonly known as the flesh-eating disease.
必须马上手术  切除坏死组织
We need to operate immediately to remove the damaged tissue.
可能得截肢
We may need to remove the leg.
-核磁共振显示有问题  -开什么玩笑
- The M.R.I. revealed a problem. - No kidding.
抱歉你的医生没尽早查出问题
I'm sorry none of your doctors found it earlier.
我个人自此将全程监督你的治疗情况
I am personally gonna oversee your treatment from now on.
你们会让我动一堆手术  是吧
You're gonna cut me open, aren't you?
可能需要截肢
We may need to remove the leg.
他的核磁共振结果显示
His M.R.I. showed that the leg pain
腿疼并非私自注射而导致
wasn't caused by the self-injection.
也不是感染引发的
It wasn't caused by an infection.
动脉瘤内血栓形成
It was an aneurysm that clotted...
导致的梗死
leading to an infarction.
天哪  你猜对了  正是豪斯自己
My God, you were right. It's House.
一定得动手术
We have to do the surgery.
坏死组织必须手术切除  如果太多的话...
The necrotic tissue has to be removed. If there's too much--
我不管你们发现了什么
I don't care what you find.
为了救你  这些都是必要措施
It may become necessary in order to save your life.
我喜欢自己的腿
I like my leg.
自我记事起  他们就跟着我
I've had it for as long as I can remember.
格雷戈  我跟你一样喜欢你的腿
Greg, I love your leg as much as you do.
绝对不能截肢
They're not cutting it off.
病人作出正确的选择
The patient made the right choice.
告诉医生  截肢也可以
Tell a surgeon that it's okay to cut a leg off,
他将抛光自己腿上的钢架度过漫漫长夜
and he's gonna spend the night polishing his good hacksaw.
对  医生对保全病人四肢根本毫不在乎
Right. Surgeons could care less about saving limbs.
医生当然关心病人权益
Of course they care about their patients.
只是关心他们自己更多而已
They just care about themselves more,
这种立场也不是不能理解
which is not an unreasonable position.
保留越多的组织
Trying to maximize the tissue you save...
风险越大
also maximizes the chances of something going wrong,
这意味着你得格外小心
which means you've gotta be extra careful,
这真是太讨厌了
which is such a pain in the ass.
医学界已经有了非凡进步  装了义肢的孩子们
Amazing advances have been made. Kids with prosthetic legs...
百米冲刺可以跑进12秒内
are running the hundred-meter dash in 12 seconds.
是啊  只是看着不太美观而已
Yeah, they're just not as pretty.
做个旁路  让血液恢复流通就好
Do a bypass. Restore the circulation.
-截肢更安全  -对你还是对我
- Amputation is safer. - For you or me?
-血流的阻塞...-已经阻塞了四天
- The blockage of blood flow--  - Four-day blockage.
对  导致肌肉细胞坏死
Yes. It caused muscle cell death.
细胞坏死会释放细胞因子和钾
When those cells die, they release cytokines and potassium.
一旦血液恢复流通  而不把坏死组织切除的话
And if you restore the blood flow instead of just lopping it all off,
这些都会重新流回我的身体系统中
then all that crap gets washed back into my system.
细胞因子可能导致器官衰竭
The cytokines could cause organ failure.
而钾可能导致心脏骤停
The potassium could cause cardiac arrest.
但另一方面  我可能能保住我的腿
On the other hand, I may just get the use of my leg back.
-光是术后的疼痛就...-我可以忍受
- The postoperative pain alone will -  - I'll get through it.
风险我都明白  你也清楚
I understand the risks. You're in the clear.
安排旁路手术吧
Go schedule an O.R.
老天  你个白痴
God, you're an idiot.
我觉得我更像个混球
I think I'm more of a jerk.
我不想跟你耍嘴皮子  也不会装可爱
I'm not being glib, and I'm not being cute.
只是不想你害死自己
I don't want you to kill yourself.
我不会死的
I'm not gonna die.
这下我还真放心了
Oh, I feel completely reassured.
再吸干净点
More suction.
现在插入
Inserting now.
让他们加大吗啡用量
They gotta up the morphine.
医生说不行
Doctors say they can't.
医生还曾推荐卧床休息和使用抗生素呢
Doctors recommended bed rest and antibiotics.
他们之前是错了
They screwed up.
但不意味着这次也错了
It doesn't mean they're wrong this time.
当然也不意味着这次就对了
Sure doesn't mean they're right.
-吗啡会害死你的  -我能熬过去的
- Morphine will kill you. - I can handle it.
你疼痛难忍  不能正确思考
You're in pain. You're not thinking right.
所以我才需要那该死的吗啡
That's why I need the damn morphine!
我去跟他们说
I'll talk to them.
上帝啊  他还得这样疼多久
Oh, my God. How much longer is the pain gonna last?
得看肌肉细胞坏死的数量
It depends on how much muscle cell death there was.
他可能是对的
He could be right.
他可能可以不用截肢就挺过去
He could come out of this with almost full use of his leg.
或者呢
Or?
或者可能余生都这么痛苦
He could be in pain for the rest of his life.
还有第三种选择  动手术
There's a third option... surgically.
是目前情况和截肢间折中的办法
A middle ground between what we did and amputation.
他不喜欢折中
He's not big on middle ground.
是啊
Yeah.
护士  护士
Nurse? Nurse!
再帮我挂葡萄糖酸钙
I need more calcium gluconate.
你已经挂了五袋了
You just had five m.l.'s.
报告显示心电图QRS波变宽
The Q.R.S. is getting wider.
钾含量一直在增加
My potassium is rising.
-我这就去找医生  -你最好快点
- I'll talk to your doctor. - Well, you better make it fast,
因为我的心脏快骤停了
'cause I'm about to go into cardiac arrest.
快帮我挂  不然心动过速会更严重
You give me the dose, or I go into wide complex tachycardia.
-我会有麻烦的  -听着  这又不是麻醉剂
- I could get in trouble-- - Listen, it's not a narcotic!
我不是在跟你讨价还价  你还有20秒
I'm not looking for a buzz. You got about 20 seconds.
我错了
I was wrong.
-什么情况  -心动过速
- What do you got? - Wide complex tachycardia.
-是你的诊断  -他自己做的诊断
- You diagnosed-- - He did.
-准备心脏除颤器  -心脏除颤器
- Defibrillator. - Paddles.
-充电  -让开
- Charge. - Clear.
病人心脏停跳超过一分钟
The patient was technically dead for over a minute.
他活过来了
He's back.
你认为他经历了死亡吗
Do you think he was dead?
你认为濒死体验是真实的吗
Do you think those experiences were real?
何谓"真实"  体验是真实发生的
Define "real". They were real experiences.
他们说的是...
What they meant--
我个人选择相信  人们常说的
Personally, I choose to believe that the white light people sometimes see,
这位病人见也到的  那道白光
the visions this patient saw,
只是大脑停止时
they're all just chemical reactions
所发生的化学反应
that take place while the brain shuts down.
你选择相信这个
You choose to believe that?
科学研究从不会有尽头
There's no conclusive science.
我的选择对我的生命没有影响
My choice has no practical relevance to my life.
我只是选择更令人欣慰的结果
I choose the outcome I find more comforting.
而你觉得这个说法更令人欣慰
You find it more comforting to believe that this is it?
我觉得相信人世不是一场单纯的试验
I find it more comforting to believe that this...
更令我欣慰
isn't simply a test.
现在有多痛
How bad is the pain right now?
非常痛
It's bad.
根本就没好转
It's not getting any better.
如果你对的话  疼痛会减少
If you were right, the pain would be subsiding.
-你也会慢慢好转  -只是时间长点
- You'd be getting better. - It's just taking longer.
不  不是的
No, it's not.
本该让他们帮你截肢的
We've gotta let 'em cut the leg off.
这是我的腿  是我的人生
It's my leg. It's my life.
如果需要你截肢救我一命  你会吗
Would you give up your leg to save my life?
当然
Of course I would.
那你怎么会认为你的命不如我的值钱
Why do you think your life is worth less than mine?
如果是其他病人  你会怎么跟他们说
If this were any other patient, what would you tell them to do?
-我会说让他们自己选择  -不可能
- I would say it's their choice. - Not a chance.
你会恐吓他们
You'd browbeat them
直到他们作出你认为对的选择
until they made the choice you knew was right.
你会冲他们嚷嚷  这只是条该死的腿
You'd shove it in their face that it's just a damn leg.
你觉得自己不该活下去吗
You don't think you deserve to live?
觉得自己不该得到幸福吗
You don't think you deserve to be happy?
让他们截肢就好了
Now let them cut off your leg.
我做不到  做不到
I can't. I can't.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
光是疼就能把你疼死
The pain alone is gonna kill you.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
帮我去跟医生说下
I need you to talk to the doctor.
他改主意了吗
He change his mind?
没有
No.
他要求对他进行化学昏迷
He's asked to be put in a chemically induced coma...
让他能在疼痛最严重的时候  一路睡过去
so that he can sleep through the worst part of the pain.
我们可以这么做
We can do that.
他昏迷之后会怎么做
What happens after he's in the coma?
当然会严密监视他的情况
We'll obviously monitor his condition closely,
如果在接下来48小时内
and if he can get through the next 48 hours
心脏没有其他状况
without another cardiac incident--
我是他的健康医疗代理
I meant, I'm his health care proxy.
他不能做决定期间  我可以代理
I get to make medical decisions for him if he's not able to.
你该跟他谈谈他想怎么做
You should talk to him about what he wants to do.
我知道他想怎么做
I know what he wants.
但在他昏迷期间  我就能做主  对吗
But if he's out, it's my call, right?
你会在一分钟内昏迷
You'll be out in less than a minute.
谢谢
Thank you.
等我醒来后再见
I'll see you when I wake up.
我们去打高尔夫
We'll go golfing.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你没什么好道歉的
You've got nothing to be sorry about.
你之前说过的折衷选择
The middle ground you were talking about--
进行手术  切除坏死肌肉
We go in, take out the dead muscle.
还是会有一些伤害的风险  但...
There's still some risk of reperfusion injury, but--
给我需要签名的表格
Give me the forms you need signed.
你这是在救他的命
You're saving his life.
他不会那么想的
He won't see it that way.
由于切除肌肉的范围太大
Because of the extent of the muscle removed,
病人腿部功能严重受损
the utility of the patient's leg was severely compromised.
由于确诊时间延误太久
Because of the time delay in making the diagnosis,
病人持续遭受慢性剧痛
the patient continues to experience chronic pain.
-她没权利那样做  -她有代理权
- She had no right to do that. - She had the proxy.
她明知他不想动手术
She knew he didn't want the surgery.
她是为了救他的命
She saved his life.
这点没人知道  也许他会好转
We don't know that. Maybe he would've been fine.
没关系  这是病人的选择
It doesn't matter. It's the patient's call.
那病人是个白痴
The patient's an idiot.
病人通常都是
They usually are.
有定时器之类的吗
Do you have a buzzer or something?
这课什么时候结束
What time does this class end?
二十分钟前
Twenty minutes ago.
我再也不干这个了
I'm not doing this again.
这家伙不是个好爸爸
And this guy is not the world's greatest dad.
排名都够不上
Not even ranked.
哪个好爸爸会给孩子用含铅的颜料
Who the hell lets their kids play with lead-based paint?
怪不得他总生病
That's why he's always sick.
帮他另找几个塑料杯  这门课就还给他了
Find him some plastic cups, and the class is all his again.
史黛西  我是格雷戈
Stacy, it's Greg.
我明早十点有空
I've got an opening in my calendar for 10:00 tomorrow morning.
务必让你丈夫别迟到
Make sure your husband isn't late.